<?teipublisher template="view-grid-prohd.html" odd="prohd.odd" view="div"?><?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="intro">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Start page content</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>
               <ref target="http://www.bbaw.de">Berlin-Brandenburgische Akademie der Wissenschaften
                  (BBAW)</ref>
            </publisher>
            <pubPlace ref="http://www.geonames.org/2950159">Berlín</pubPlace>
            <availability status="free">
               <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons
                  Atribución 4.0 Internacional (CC BY 4.0) </licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Born digital</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <group>
         <text xml:lang="de">
            <body>
               <div>
                  <p>
                     Das Proyecto Humboldt Digital (ProHD) ist eine internationale Initiative zur Fortbildung in den Digital 
                     Humanities an zwei Standorten: Havanna (Casa Museo Alejandro de Humboldt) und Berlin (Berlin-Brandenburgische 
                     Akademie der Wissenschaften).
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     Das Projekt fokussiert sich auf das Erforschen der kubanischen wissenschaftlichen und literarischen Kultur 
                     des 18. und 19. Jahrhunderts, insbesondere auf die Erschließung von Quellen, die für Alexander von Humboldts 
                     Kuba-Forschung in der Zeit von 1800-1830 relevant sind.
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     Dieses <hi>Digitale Dossier: Alexander von Humboldt und Kuba (1800-1830)</hi> enthält Transkriptionen von 
                     handschriftlichen Textdokumenten in drei Sprachen (Englisch, Französisch und Spanisch). Sie alle 
                     beziehen sich auf Humboldts Reise nach Kuba und die Fragen, die der preußische Wissenschaftler in dem 
                     <hi>Essai politique sur l'île de Cuba</hi> (2 Bände, Paris 1826) untersucht hat.
                  </p>
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
         <text xml:lang="es">
            <body>
               <div>
                  <p>
                  El Proyecto Humboldt Digital (ProHD) es una iniciativa internacional para la formación avanzada en Humanidades 
                  Digitales en dos lugares: La Habana (Casa Museo Alejandro de Humboldt) y Berlín (Academia de Ciencias y 
                  Humanidades de Berlín-Brandeburgo).
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     El proyecto se centra en el estudio de la cultura científica y literaria cubana de los siglos XVIII y 
                     XIX, especialmente en la exploración de fuentes relevantes para la investigación de Alexander von 
                     Humboldt sobre Cuba durante el periodo de 1800-1830.
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     Este <hi>Dossier Digital: Alexander von Humboldt y Cuba (1800-1830)</hi> contiene transcripciones de documentos 
                     textuales manuscritos en tres idiomas (inglés, francés y español). Todos ellos se refieren al viaje de 
                     Humboldt a Cuba y a las cuestiones que el científico prusiano estudió en el <hi>Essai politique sur l'île 
                     de Cuba</hi> (2 vols., París 1826).
                  </p>
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
      
         <text xml:lang="en">
            <body>
               <div>
                  <p>
                     Proyecto Humboldt Digital (ProHD) is an international initiative for advanced training in the Digital Humanities at two locations: Havana (Casa Museo Alejandro de Humboldt) and Berlin (Berlin-Brandenburg Academy of Sciences and Humanities).
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     The project focuses on the study of Cuban scientific and literary culture of the 18th and 19th centuries, especially on the exploration of sources relevant to Alexander von Humboldt's research on Cuba during the period of 1800–1830.
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     This  <hi>Digital Dossier: Alexander von Humboldt and Cuba (1800–1830)</hi> contains transcriptions of 
                     textual documents in manuscript in three languages (English, French, and Spanish). They all relate to 
                     Humboldt's trip to Cuba and the questions the Prussian scientist studied in the 
                     <hi>Essai politique sur l'île de Cuba</hi> (2 vols., Paris 1826).
                  </p>  
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
      </group>
   </text>
</TEI>