<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="intro">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>About the project</title>
            <editor>
               <persName ref="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8916-4997">
                  <surname>Rojas Castro</surname>
                  <forename>Antonio</forename>
               </persName>
            </editor>
            <funder ref="https://www.auswaertiges-amt.de/de/">Auswärtiges Amt</funder>
            <funder ref="https://www.fritz-thyssen-stiftung.de/">Fritz Thyssen Stiftung</funder>
            <funder ref="https://www.gerda-henkel-stiftung.de/">Gerda Henkel Stiftung</funder>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>
               <ref target="http://www.bbaw.de">Berlin-Brandenburgische Akademie der Wissenschaften
                  (BBAW)</ref>
            </publisher>
            <pubPlace ref="http://www.geonames.org/2950159">Berlin</pubPlace>
            <availability status="free">
               <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons
                  Attribution 4.0 International (CC BY 4.0) </licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Born digital</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <head>Introduction</head>
            <p>
               <hi rendition="#b">Proyecto Humboldt Digital (ProHD)</hi> is an international
               initiative for continuing education in the digital humanities, which is located in
               Havana (Casa Museo Alejandro de Humboldt) and Berlin (Berlin-Brandenburg Academy of
               Sciences and Humanities).</p>
            <p>The project focuses on the study of Cuban scientific and literary culture of the 18th
               and 19th centuries, especially on the exploration of sources relevant to Alexander
               von Humboldt's research on Cuba during the period of 1800–1830.</p>
            <p>The project started in 2019 and is scheduled for completion in 2023. It has been
               funded thanks to generous support from the Auswärtiges Amt, Fritz Thyssen Stiftung
               and Gerda Henkel Stiftung.</p>
            <p>To learn more about the resources created by the project, refer to the following
               links:</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <ref target="https://habanaberlin.hypotheses.org/">Blog</ref>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <ref target="https://github.com/humboldtdigital">Github</ref>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <ref target="https://prohd.ohc.cu/xmlui/">Digital repository</ref>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div>
            <head>Editorial principles</head>
            <p>The "Digital Dossier: Alexander von Humboldt and Cuba (1800–1830)" contains
               transcriptions of textual documents in manuscript and printed format, in four
               languages (English, French, German and Spanish). They all relate to Humboldt's trip
               to Cuba and the questions the Prussian scientist studied in the <title>Essai
                  politique sur l'île de Cuba</title>. The textual sources of the editions published
               in the "Digital Dossier" stem from libraries and archives in Germany, Cuba and
               Poland. FThe text of the editions is available in a double presentation: on the one
               hand, in the diplomatic transcription, the historical particularities of the source,
               such as abbreviations, original spellings, accentuation, word unions, punctuation
               marks and obvious errors, have been preserved; on the other hand, in the standardised
               text, abbreviations have been resolved, spelling, accentuation, word spacing and
               punctuation have been regularised, and obvious errors have been corrected in order to
               improve the readability of the text. The text of the editions is available in a
               double presentation: on the one hand, in the diplomatic transcription, the historical
               particularities of the source, such as abbreviations, original spellings,
               accentuation, word unions, punctuation marks and obvious errors, have been preserved;
               on the other hand, in the standardised text, abbreviations have been resolved,
               spelling, accentuation, word spacing and punctuation have been regularised, and
               obvious errors have been corrected in order to improve the readability of the text.
               or more information on the documents' provenance, please consult the metadata section
               of each edition.</p>
            <p>The text of the editions is available in a double presentation: on the one hand, in
               the diplomatic transcription, the historical particularities of the source, such as
               abbreviations, original spellings, accentuation, word unions, punctuation marks and
               obvious errors, have been preserved; on the other hand, in the standardised text,
               abbreviations have been resolved, spelling, accentuation, word spacing and
               punctuation have been regularised, and obvious errors have been corrected in order to
               improve the readability of the text.</p>
         </div>
         <div>
            <head>Technical Aspects</head>
            <p>All the texts and the corresponding metadata published in the "Digital Dossier" have
               been encoded in XML format following the <ref target="https://tei-c.org/">Text
                  Encoding Initiative</ref> (P5) Guidelines. To facilitate the encoding task, the
               framework ediarum developed by TELOTA has been adapted resulting in <ref
                  target="https://github.com/humboldtdigital/ediarum.PROHD.edit"
                  >ediarum.PROHD.edit</ref>.</p>
            <p>The TEI markup captures metadata about the documents, such as the source, those
               responsible for the edition and, whenever possible, the authorship and other data
               related to the creation of the texts. Regarding the texts themselves, the following
               information is encoded: Pagination of the original source, headings and paragraphs,
               divisions and logical divisions of letters, changes in typography, authorial
               interventions such as strikethroughs or additions, uncertain readings, gaps, supplied
               words, etc. For more details on our TEI markup, it is recommended to consult the
               ediarum documentation available in <ref
                  target="https://www.ediarum.org/docs/ediarum.BASE.manual/">German</ref> and <ref
                  target="https://www.ediarum.org/docs/ediarum.BASE.manual_es/">Spanish</ref>.</p>
            <p>This web application has been built with <ref
                  target="https://teipublisher.com/index.html">TEI Publisher</ref> (v. 7.0.0.) and
                  <ref target="http://exist-db.org/exist/apps/homepage/index.html">eXistDB</ref> (v.
               5.2.0.). An ODD called prohd.xml is used to style the editions and static pages and
               two templates called prohd.html and view-grid-prohd.html are used to build the
               graphical user interface with web components. A copy of the files that make up the
               web application is available at the <ref
                  target="https://github.com/humboldtdigital/ProHD">project's Github
                  repository</ref>. Both the web application and the facsimiles are hosted on
               servers of the Oficina del Historiador de la Ciudad de La Habana; the facsimiles use
                  <ref target="https://iiif.io/">IIIF</ref>'s API.</p>
            <p>The development of the framework ediarum.PROHD.edit and of this web application has
               been carried out by Antonio Rojas Castro with the collaboration of Violeta López.
               Technical inquiries can be directed to antonio.rojas-castro [at] bbaw.de.</p>
         </div>
         <div>
            <head>Legal aspects</head>
            <p>All contents of the "Digital Dossier" are published under a <ref
                  target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en">Creative Commons
                  license CC BY 4.0</ref>. Accordingly, it is permitted to share (copy and
               redistribute the material in any medium or format) and adapt (remix, transform, and
               build upon the material for any purpose, even commercially); please give appropriate
               credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made.</p>
         </div>
         <div>
            <head>Recommended citation</head>
            <p>You may cite the "Digital Dossier" in its entirety as follows:</p>
            <p>Kraft, Tobias (dir.). <title>Digital Dossier: Alexander von Humboldt and Cuba
                  (1800-1830)</title>, Berlin-Brandenburgische Akademie der Wissenschaften and
               Oficina del Historiador de la Ciudad de la Habana, 2021-2023.</p>
            <p>Or a specific individual edition:</p>
            <p>Arango y Parreño, Francisco de. "Observaciones sobre el Ensayo politico con relacion
               a la Isla de Cuba que ha escrito el Señor Baron de Humboldt". <title>Digital Dossier:
                  Alexander von Humboldt and Cuba (1800-1830)</title>, Kathrin Kraller (ed.),
               Berlin-Brandenburgische Akademie der Wissenschaften and Oficina del Historiador de la
               Ciudad de la Habana, 2021.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
